Privacy Policy
==============

Encryptomatic LLC Privacy Policy  
--------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------

**Effective from 4th of January, 2019.**

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, and shared when you visit or make a purchase from //www.encryptomatic.com or other sites owned and operated by us (the Site).

### PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

When you visit the Site, certain information about your device is collected, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or products that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as â€œDevice Information.

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

* Cookies are data files that are placed on your device or computer and often include an anonymous unique identifier. For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit //www.allaboutcookies.org.
* Log files track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.
* Web beacons, tags, and pixels are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.

Additionally when you make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through the Site, we collect certain information from you, including your name, billing address, shipping address, payment information (including credit card numbers, email address, and phone number. We refer to this information as Order Information.

This information is held for us by trusted vendors who process and fulfill orders and perform certain business functions on our behalf, including Authorize.net, 2Checkout, Amazon, eBay, Ultracart and Kunaki Inc.

When we talk about Personal Information in this Privacy Policy, we are talking both about Device Information and Order Information.

### Cookies

You can choose to restrict or block access to cookies set by Encryptomatic LLC or any other company. Cookies are small files created by websites you visit. They can make your online experience easier by saving browsing information. With cookies, websites can keep you signed in, remember your site preferences, and give you locally relevant content. You can [set your browser](https://support.google.com/chrome/answer/95647?co=GENIE.Platform%3DDesktop&hl=en) to notify you when a web server attempts to write or load a cookie to your computer. This gives you a chance to accept or reject the cookie. Nearly every website on the internet stores cookies when you visit it. For more information about controlling cookies, visit [allaboutcookies.org](https://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### HOW DO WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?

We use the Order Information that we collect generally to fulfill any orders placed through the Site (including processing your payment information, arranging for shipping, and providing you with invoices and/or order confirmations). Additionally, we use this Order Information to:  
Communicate with you;  
Screen our orders for potential risk or fraud; and  
When in line with the preferences you have shared with us, provide you with information or advertising relating to our products or services.

We use the Device Information that we collect to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns). We may also utilize advertising retargeting services commonly offered by Google, Bing and other ad platforms.

### SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We share your Personal Information with certain third parties to help us use your Personal Information, as described above. For example, we use Ultracart to power our online store including the shopping card hosted at secure.encryptomatic.com – you can read more about how Ultracart uses your Personal Information here: www.ultracart.com/legal/privacypolicy.html. We also use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Site–you can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: //www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/. You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: //tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout

Generally, when any information is shared with our vendors it is to assist Encryptomatic LLC market its products and acquire customers for its products. We do not presently show, nor do we intend to display ads for any 3rd party advertiser.

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

### BEHAVIORAL ADVERTISING

As described above, we use your Personal Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications from Encryptomatic LLC (such as new product announcements, update announcements or special product pricing) that we believe may be of interest to you. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative's (NAI) educational page at //www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work.

You can opt out of targeted advertising by:

FACEBOOK – //www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads  
GOOGLE – //www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous  
BING – //advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance's opt-out portal at: //optout.aboutads.info/.

As a small business, we utilize the common advertising platforms that are available to us and other U.S.A.-based small businesses to market our products, but we are not the provider of the platform. Your efforts to control your privacy are well served by making your preferences known directly to the major platform provides, including Facebook, Google, Bing, among others. Controlling your information on these platforms will necessarily impact the data that these platforms provide to us or collect from us, and will affect the methods we can use to reach you with our advertising messages.

### DO NOT TRACK

Although we would like to respect Do Not Track (DNT) requests, we find that we are hamstrung by the larger advertising platforms we need to use to conduct our business, and therefor we have little control over web browser Do Not Track requests. Companies like Google, for example, do not natively respect DNT and limit our ability to force then to respect DNT. In the past we've tried writing JS code to only fire Google Analytics requests if DNT is not detected, but this simply has not been effective or stable. Since using Google's platform is a necessary way for us to reach customers with news about our products, it places us in a difficult "all or nothing situation, where we either respect DNT by removing the entire Google platform, or we stay in business by using those platforms without any resonable control over DNT. You may be able to use [Google's analytic's opt-out browser add-in](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout) to impact DNT requests. It's a worth a look, anyway. For the time being, until we ourselves are able to effectively respect DNT requests, or until major platform provides like Google provide us this capability, please assume that we unable to, and therefor do not, alter our Site's data collection and use practices when your browser sends a Do Not Track signal.

### YOUR RIGHTS

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please contact us through the contact information below.

Additionally, if you are a European resident we note that we are processing your information in order to fulfill contracts we might have with you (for example if you make an order through the Site), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Additionally, please note that your information will be transferred outside of Europe to our servers in the United States.

### DATA RETENTION

When you place an order through the Site, Encryptomatic LLC will maintain your Order Information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information. We retain customer contact information indefinitely or at our discretion, so we can provide customer support services, product updates and security notices. We may retain this information on our own servers, or on the servers of 3rd parties that provide CRM or other business services to us, such as Ultracart or Hubspot.For example, if you bought a product from us 10 years ago and now you need our assistance to recover a lost product key, our customer support team will use this information to assist you.

### CHANGES

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons.

### Contact Information

We invite you to contact us if you have questions about this privacy policy. Our primary Internet address is [https://www.encryptomatic.com](https://www.encryptomatic.com/)  
Encryptomatic LLC  
1630 1st Ave. N.  
Suite B - 8  
Fargo, ND 58102

You may contact us by e-mail at info@encryptomatic.com or by phone on 1-701-566-6731 x2.

### Quick Links

© 2005, Encryptomatic LLC. Fargo, ND, USA.
